The Honorable member Maggie Barry thank
you Mr Speaker it is with pleasure that
I Rise to talk at the third reading of
the insurance credential supervision
Amendment bill um this is a piece of
legislation which is another significant
step in achieving clear robust
regulatory Arrangements across our
financial sector and in keeping with
much of the other fine legislation that
this John keed government has passed it
is specializing in cutting red tape and
also cutting compliance costs now as
we've heard labor supports this bill um
at select committee it went through very
well there were couple of submissions we
had four submissions and we heard from
two submitters who recommended a change
to the provision of interim financial
information requirements all very
straightforward really um I agree in
fact and share Dr David Parker's
approval of the transition process and
that the Reserve Bank give oversight to
all insurers that they be licensed and
supervised by the bank and they also
have to comply with credential
requirements because the Reserve Bank
will be both the regulator and the
supervisor and I think that will give
great peace of mind really to uh people
in New Zealand who are worried about
their insurance issues I would have to
say that for the member who just resumed
his seat um who generally takes um sort
of dull and smugness to a ridiculous
extreme um he's now clearly boyed up by
his prospects and Contender number two
is proving he is somebody who has a
little bit of life in him yet he talks
about risks and consequences something
he knows quite a lot about and I guess
when it comes to seismic upheaval which
I suppose was a general weak theme of
his discourse uh then once again it's
something he's fairly familiar with as
someone who who has experienced rather a
lot of it in his own party much of it I
feel of his own making he is of course
irretrievably dull and not widely liked
by his own caucus but uh there's
probably not enough time in this
particular call to go into that in any
detail the greens of course don't
support the bill nothing new there they
don't really support anything that
encourages growth jobs mining any kind
of improvement to the economy uh they
are of course consistent uh and that is
not a bad thing really because at least
you know where you are with them
although I think their hopes of getting
uh any kind of financial
responsibilities uh under labor if ever
they attained the uh treasury benches
have diminished somewhat one of the
final things I would say in this call is
that it empowers The Reserve Bank to
publish and maintain on its website an
official register of licensed insurers
um that is going to have additional
content in it which for the first time
will actually make it easy for people to
shop around to find out who's good and
who's not in much the same way that the
labor party is doing but with very
limited success thank you Mr Speaker I
commend this bill to the
house I call The Honorable member Andrew
Williams thank you